hey everybody welcome to this a one
English listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension as I speak
before we start remember to subscribe to
the channel click on the bell and follow
us on Instagram you ready so today I'm
gonna talk about jobs this is a really
common topic because most adults have a
job or some type of work let's talk
about the different types of jobs that
people have one common type of job is a
part-time job a part-time job is a job
where you work fewer hours I have
part-time jobs when I was younger I
worked part-time at a clothing store at
a restaurant and at my university many
students have part-time jobs they study
in the morning and work in the evening I
did this when I was a student in the
u.s. many teenagers get a job when
they're in high school I got my first
job when I was 17 I was in my last year
of high school
I worked at a clothing store called
Hollister I didn't like that job but I
liked earning money some of my
classmates worked at fast-food
restaurants like McDonald's I also had a
part-time job when I was in college when
I was in college I worked at the
university's dining hall a dining hall
is the place on a university campus
where students eat I worked as a cook
and a dishwasher at my dining hall I
didn't like washing dishes
I liked cooking more than dishwashing
how about you have you ever had a
part-time job okay now let's talk about
full-time jobs in the US people who have
full-time jobs usually work 40 hours
week or more some people work a lot more
like 50 or 60 hours a week for some
full-time jobs you need a college degree
for other full-time jobs you don't need
a degree in the u.s. there are many
different jobs available in different
industries
some examples of industries are finance
marketing medicine IT and education I
work in the education industry because
I'm a teacher there are many good jobs
in the US for people who don't have
degrees for example you can be an
electrician a plumber a truck driver or
many other things people who have these
jobs make good money in the u.s. most
salaries in America are high compared to
other countries
Americans make a lot of money but they
have to spend a lot of money
life is very expensive in the u.s. the
normal schedule for full-time jobs is
from 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. in the US
however some people start work earlier
like at 8:00 a.m.
and other people and later like at 6:00
p.m. I start work pretty early at 7:30
a.m. but I also finished early at 4:30
p.m.
I prefer starting work early and
finishing work early most people work
Monday to Friday and they have weekends
off most people don't like working on
the weekends I work in the morning on
Saturdays but I have Sundays off I never
work on Sundays how about you what's
your work schedule alright that's all
for today leave a comment and tell me
about your job and remember to subscribe
to the channel click on the bell and
follow us on Instagram for more English
tips and lessons I'll see you next time
[Music]
[Applause]